soundation.com 2019-04-21

# Soundation — Privacy Policy

Privacy Policy  
Valid starting on the 24th of May, 2018.  
Table of contents  
1 Introduction  
2 What is personal data and what does the processing of personal data mean?   
3\. For whom is this policy applicable?   
4\. For what areas is this policy applicable?  
5\. What does it mean to be a Data Controller?   
6\. Soundation as a Data Controller  
7\. Why are we allowed to process personal data?   
8\. What personal data do we process and why?  
9\. How long do we generally store personal data?  
10\. Our actions to protect personal data  
11\. When do we share personal data?  
12\. Your rights  
13\. Cookies  
14\. Changes to this policy  
15\. Contact

1\. Introduction  
Thank you for choosing to use our service and a special thanks for taking the time to thoroughly read through this Privacy Policy. We would like to begin with a short summary explaining why we have created this policy. Our fundamental objectives are to:  
Give you a brief introduction to personal data;  
Explain why we handle certain kinds of personal information;  
Ensure that you understand what information we gather and what we actually do with said information;   
Show you how we work to protect your rights and your integrity.  
Our goal is that you, after having read this policy, will feel secure in that your personal integrity is respected and that your personal data is treated in a correct manner. We therefore also work on a continuous basis with securing that our treatment of personal data is completely in compliance with current legislation, especially the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) which will be in effect as of May the 25th, 2018.

2\. What is personal data and what does the processing of personal data mean?   
2.1 Personal data consists of all information that directly, or indirectly together with other information, can be connected to a living (physical) person. A non-exhaustive list with examples of personal data consists of, among others:  
Name  
Personal ID number  
Email-address  
IP-address  
Pictures and video

2.2 The Processing of personal data includes every action connected to the use of the personal data, regardless of whether such an action is performed automatically or not. This means that the following actions, among others, are included:  
Collection  
Registration  
Use  
Alteration  
Storage  
Disclosure by transmission  
Deletion

3\. For whom is this policy applicable?   
This Privacy Policy shall in the first instance be applicable to individuals who are users of our Services and from whom we collect and process personal data (”Data Subjects”). Different parts of this Privacy Policy may also be relevant to you depending on your relationship with us. All in all, this policy is relevant for persons who:   
are customers or users of ours – when handling your account in order to provide you with the best possible user experience  
visit our website or our social media platforms  
otherwise communicate with us, for example through our customer service  
By agreeing to this Privacy Policy you agree to our processing of your personal data in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

4\. For what areas is this policy applicable?   
This Privacy Policy regulates how we may collect and process personal data to be able to continue delivering and developing our Services.

5\. What does it mean to be a Data Controller?  
A Data Controller is a legal person or other entity that determines the purpose and means for the processing of personal data. A corporation is a Data Controller in regards to personal data it has for its own benefit in regards to its employees, customers, partners, users and others.

6\. Soundation as a Data Controller  
We, Soundation AB (company reg. no. 556561-6629) are the Data Controller and therefore accountable in accordance with applicable legislation, for the processing that occurs with your personal data, within the scope of our Services.

7\. Why are we allowed to process personal data?  
7.1 For it to be permissible for us to process personal data there must always be support for said treatment within the GDPR, so-called lawful basis. Such lawful basis may include:   
Consent from the Data Subject.  
That the processing of personal data is necessary to fulfill the terms of an agreement with the Data Subject, for example in relation to the use of the Services.  
Fulfilling a legal obligation, for example storing certain information due to legislation regarding certain accounting standards and practices. This could also be the case when handling opt-out settings requests concerning your rights as a Data Subject in accordance with GDPR.  
A weighing of interests when we have a legitimate interest in using your data, for example for statistical purposes and to market our services, and to secure payment and prevent fraud.  
7.2 It may occur that the same personal data is processed both through support in terms of fulfilling an agreement as well as in terms of specific consent or in terms of the processing of that specific information is necessary to fulfill other legal obligations. This means that even though you may revoke your consent and the treatment based on said consent ceases, that specific personal data may remain with us for separate reasons.

8\. What personal data do we process, and why?  
In this section, we explain how your personal data is used in order for us to be able to provide you with relevant experiences, services, and offers.  
8.1 When you sign up for our Services  
When you register an account at soundation.com we handle the following personal data which you personally provide to us:  
Your name and your contact information  
Your credit card number and bank information, stored by our payment provider and in compliance with PCI DSS (security requirements for businesses that store, process or transmit cardholder data)  
8.1.1 We handle your personal data in order to:  
Identify you as a user  
Charge you for the services and products that you have ordered  
In order to discover, and prevent, fraud in conjunction with bank card payments  
Handle and deliver what you have purchased in accordance with our terms and conditions  
Notifying you (through email, or similar) regarding information connected to your usage of our Services   
Market our Services and products, for example by email  
Produce statistics regarding purchases and usage, in order to improve our services  
Prevent any type of intellectual property infringement  
8.1.2 Legal grounds for the processing   
We process your personal data based on:   
performance of a contract when we provide our Services;   
based upon a weighing of interests when we have a legitimate interest in using your data for statistical purposes and to market our services, as well as to secure payment and prevent fraud and   
based upon a legal obligation for handling opt-out settings requests concerning your rights in accordance with the GDPR  
8.1.3 Period of storage  
We save data about you for up to 12 months after termination of your user account, among other reasons to provide information regarding any complaints.

8.2 Users and members of Soundation  
When you are a user of our Services, in addition to the provisions described in sections 8.1, we also process:  
data about your user account, for example, user number and subscription  
data about your usage of our Services  
data about your purchasing history with Soundation  
8.2.1 The personal data is processed in order to:  
administer your user account   
analyze and categorize you in relation to our other users based on information you have provided to us and based on how you use our services (musical style, preferences and purchasing history)  
inform you of personal and tailor-made offers, campaigns, and benefits from us and our cooperating partners, for example by email   
produce statistics and carry out analytical actions in order to develop our services and offers, including long-term analytical actions in order to understand trends over time  
ensure the security of our Services, and discover or prevent various types of unlawful use, or use which otherwise contravenes the terms and conditions of our Services  
8.2.2 Legal grounds for the processing:   
We process your personal data based on   
performance of a contract when we fulfill our obligations towards you as a user (for example administering your user account and providing relevant offers) and   
based on a weighing of interests when we have a legitimate interest in using data about your usage of the service and your purchasing history to produce statistics needed to develop, improve, and ensure the functionality and security of our services.  
8.2.3 Period of storage:   
We save your personal data during the time that you have an active account at soundation.com and for up to 12 months after the termination of the said account. In order to ensure traceability, we save data regarding our communications with you for 12 months.

8.3 Persons with a login account  
When you have a login account, in addition to the provisions described in sections 8.1, 8.2, we also process:  
data about your login account, for example, username and password  
data which you personally choose to save in your profile, for example name, contact information, etc.  
data regarding your musical preferences and purchasing history, or how you otherwise use our services or our digital channels, for example, information regarding your most recent logins  
8.3.1 The personal data is processed in order to:  
administer your login account  
contact you with information and general offers, for example by email  
produce statistics and carry out analytical actions to improve our services, goods, and offers, including long-term analytical actions needed to understand trends over time  
provide, maintain, test, improve and develop the digital services and the technical platform used to provide our Services  
ensure the security of our Services in order to discover or prevent various types of unlawful use, or use which otherwise breaches the terms and conditions  
8.3.2 Legal grounds for the processing:   
We process your personal data based on the   
performance of a contract when we provide our Services  
8.3.3 Period of storage:   
We save your login information as long as you actively use your login account (up to 6 months after the last use) or have an active account with us. In order to ensure traceability, we save data regarding our communications with you for 12 months.  
8.4 When you communicate with us  
You can choose to communicate with us in many different ways, for example via social media and emails with our customer service.  
When you communicate with us, we process data which you personally provide to us, for example:  
name and contact information  
information regarding your views, questions, or matters  
8.4.1 We process your personal data in order to:  
answer questions and handle your matters, for example addressing defects, handling complaints, questions about your musical content  
improve our services and the information we provide and publish on our website  
8.4.2 Legal grounds for the processing:   
We process your personal data for our, and your, legitimate interest in administering your matter (weighing of interests).  
8.4.3 Period of storage:   
We save your personal data for up to 12 months after the matter is closed in order to ensure traceability in your communications with us.

9\. How long do we generally store personal data?  
Your personal data is stored only during the period for which there is a need to store the information to be able to fulfill the terms of the agreement. We may store your personal data longer if this is necessary from a legal standpoint or to safeguard our legal interests, for example within the scope of legal proceedings that we are involved in.

10\. Our actions to protect personal data  
10.1 We have ensured that we have taken all necessary and appropriate technical and organizational measures to safeguard your personal data against loss, misuse or unauthorized access.   
10.2 To technically ensure that personal data is processed in a safe and confidential manner we use digital networks that are breach protected through for example encryption, firewalls, and password protection. In any instance where a breach may occur we have created routines to identify, assess and minimize any damage that may occur as well as inform said damage to all affected parties.  
10.3 To ensure an adequate knowledge level regarding the processing of personal data we will arrange ongoing educational efforts regarding GDPR, both for our employees as well as the consultants that may from time to another be contracted to do work for us.

11\. When do we share personal data?   
11.1 We will not sell, make available or spread personal data to third parties with the exception of what is stated throughout this Privacy Policy. Within the scope of the Services, personal data may be shared with subcontractors or partners, if this is necessary for the fulfillment and performance of our Services, for example, to process your payments. In any instance where we choose to share personal data we will enter into a Data Processing Agreement to ensure that the recipient of the personal data processes said information in accordance with applicable legislation as well as to ensure that the recipient has taken the necessary technical and organizational actions to, in a satisfactory fashion, be able to protect the rights and freedoms of you as a Data Subject.  
11.2 Furthermore we may share personal data if we are required to do so by law, court order or if withholding such personal data would hinder an ongoing legal investigation.

12\. Your rights  
12.1 We are responsible for your personal data being processed in accordance with applicable legislation.   
12.2 Upon your request, or at our own initiative, we will correct, de-identify, delete or complete any information that has been found to be wrongful, incomplete or misleading.   
12.3 You have the right to demand access to your personal data. This means that you have the right to demand transcripts regarding the processing that we have maintained over your personal data. You also have the right to receive a copy of the personal data that are being processed. You have the right to, once a year and through written application, without cost receive a transcript regarding what personal data is stored in regards to you, the purpose of the storage and processing as well as to whom said information has been made accessible. You also have, within the transcripts, the right to be informed of the period of time in which the personal data will be stored and what criteria we have used to determine that period of time.   
12.4 You have the right of correction of your personal data. We will, upon your request and as quickly as possible correct the incorrect or incomplete personal data we process in regards to you.   
12.5 You have the right to demand deletion of your personal data. This means that you have the right to demand that your personal data is removed if it is no longer necessary for the objectives for which it was gathered. There may exist legal requirements stating that we may not immediately delete personal data (for example in terms of auditing and taxation related legislation). We will in any such case cease the processing being done for any other reasons than to adhere to the legislation of GDPR.  
12.6 You have the right to object to any processing of personal data that is carried out on a lawful basis of weighing of interests. If you object to such processing we will only continue the processing if there are legitimate reasons for the processing that outweigh your interests.  
12.7 You have the right to report our processing of your personal data to any public authority responsible for monitoring the application of the GDPR, for example, The Swedish Data Protection Authority in Sweden. However, we do recommend that you contact us first so that we can try solving the matter in a more efficient and timely manner.

13\. Cookies  
When you visit our website, we may also collect information and data about you by using what is referred to as cookies. A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic logging cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not.

14\. Changes to this policy   
We reserve the right to make amendments to this Privacy Policy from time to another. The date for the latest amendment is stated at the end of this Privacy Policy. If we make any amendments to the Privacy Policy we will publish these amendments on our website. You are therefore recommended to read this Privacy Policy regularly to view any potential amendments.

15\. Contact  
Soundation AB (company reg. no. 556561-6629) is the Data Controller for the processing of your personal data. If you would like to have additional information on how your personal data is handled, please contact us through a written and personally signed request sent to:  
Soundation AB  
Mailbox 2452 36  
111 75 Stockholm  
Sweden  
In the letter, please include your name, address, email, telephone number and personal ID number. Please also enclose a copy of your ID. A reply will be sent to your email address.
